## Jeff Losee

SLC, UT

T: 801.872.3456 E: jeff@jaldev.com P: www.jaldev.com

Brief

I have a passion for the web, emerging technologies, and understanding how the world works. I have 10+ years experience working with various e-commerce and traditional CMS platforms, and creating custom intuitive database driven apps. I bring an incredibly varied skill-set to the table, and can excel at most steps in the development lifecycle. Significant leadership experience and experience with high traffic, critical applications. Have developed and integrated numerous APIs, including integrations with many maybe CRMs, ERPs, shipping companies, and payment processors.

Experience

JALDev, Freelance Developer – January 2008-Current

Through my site, <a href="http://www.jaldev.com">http://www.jaldev.com</a>. and word of mouth I've maintained an active list of clients, everything from NBC Universal to local plumbers. Most recently I've been working with the University of Utah and the Department of Health.

Magento \* PHP \* MYSQL \* jQuery \* CSS/SASS \* Node \* Composer \* Laravel \* Client Relations \* React \* Full Stack \* Angular \* API Development \* AWS

Cricut, Senior Software Engineer – September 2016-May 2017

Worked on an enterprise scale Magento site, receiving millions of view a month. Implementing custom modules and speed optimization to assist organization needs. Skills needed included a deep understanding of shell scripting, GIT, PHP, and AWS cloud technologies. Lead a team of in-house and off shore resources. Created a custom API to access and store customer data and statistics for other internal and external projects.

Magento \* PHP \* MYSQL \* AWS \* Dev Ops \* Continuous Integration \* API Development/ Integration \* Team Lead \* Enterprise Sites \* Site Scalability \* Angular

Love Communications, Lead Interactive Developer – December 2013-August 2016

I came in when the team was a bit short staffed and was able to quickly get up to speed and start getting projects out the door. One of the things they could always rely on was if a project was passed to me I'd find a way to get it done. Other duties involved attending client meetings, managing expectations, assisting with RFPs, preliminary research, and delegating and leading the rest of the team.

Magento \* PHP \* MYSQL \* jQuery \* Node\* CSS/SASS \* Laravel \* CAKE \* Linux/Apache Setup \* Amazon Web Services \* CAKE \* Team Lead \* API Development \* Angular

AtTask, Full-Stack Developer – February 2012-January 2013

Responsible for completing the rebranding and launch of the website with a small team under a tight deadline. The project launched on time and was a large success due to our teams efficiency and creative input. Site was built to be scalable and serve millions of views a month to accolade enterprise level customers.

Wordpress \* PHP \* MySQL \* HTML/CSS/LESS \* Angular \* Enterprise Sites \* Site Scalability

OozleMedia, Lead Developer - March 2009-December 2011

Worked closely with a designer to implement many custom PHP/sMySQL solutions, as well as Wordpress, Magento, and Flash. Managed project deadlines and client expectations.

Wordpress \* Magento \* PHP \* MYSQL \* jQuery \* Flash \* Flex \* Design \* SASS \* Amazon Web Services \* Team Lead

Jandaco, Web Developer - January 2005-February 2009

Filled various roles, including front-end and back-end work in PHP, MySQL, ActionScript, and managing client relationships. Integrated sites into a variety of content management systems including Movable Type and Expression Engine. Clients included Disney, HBO, and other large properties totaling 10s of millions of views a month.

Wordpress \* Movable Type \* Expression Engine \* Flash \* Agile/SCRUM \* CAKE \* Enterprise Sites

Education & Accolades

Dixie State University **Bachelor of Technology. - BTech, Software Engineer** 2003-2004 Attended a year at the *National Academy of IT* program as a senior, where I excelled and received an introduction to fields such as C#, Microsoft Office (Excel, Word, Powerpoint, etc), HTML, and Flash

Jordan Applied Tech Center Vocational Training 2002

Attended a year at the *National Academy of IT* program as a senior, where I excelled and received an introduction to fields such as C#, Microsoft Office (Excel, Word, Powerpoint, etc), HTML, and Flash

Lego Batman Game Gold Addy + Judges Choice 2009

Primary Skills PHP - MySQL - HTML/CSS - Javascript/AJAX - Wordpress - Magento \* Leadership \* API De-

velopment/Integration - Angular

Software/Frameworks Magento - Wordpress - Movable Type - jQuery - Prototype - Zend - Git - Gulp - NodeJS

Laravel - Symfony - Composer - LAMP Stack - Database Design - Angular - Memcache.

REDIS - React

References http://www.linkedin.com/pub/jeff-losee/